In America can a man be guilty until proven innocent?
Absence of Malice is a drama, romance film directed by Sydney Pollack.
Megan Carter is a reporter duped into running an untrue story
on Michael Gallagher, a suspected racketeer.
He has an alibi for the time his crime was allegedly
committed—but it involves an innocent party.
When he tells Carter the truth and the newspaper runs it, tragedy follows, forcing Carter to
face up to the responsibilities of her job when she is confronted by Gallagher.
Megan Carter, played by Sally Field.
Michael Colin Gallagher, played by Paul Newman.
Elliott Rosen, played by Bob Balaban.
Teresa Perrone, played by Melinda Dillon.
Santos Malderone, played by Luther Adler.
Robert Waddell, played by Barry Primus.
Absence of Malice is a 1981 American drama neo noir thriller film directed by Sydney Pollack and
starring Paul Newman, Sally Field, Wilford Brimley, Melinda Dillon and Bob Balaban.
The title refers to one of the defenses against libel defamation.
It is used in journalism classes to illustrate the conflict between disclosing
damaging personal information and the public's right to know.
The film explores themes of murder, prosecutor, newspaper
reporter, labor union, legal thriller.
The tone is emotional.